let's now speak briefly about stochastic
现在让我们简要地谈论一下随机
games this is a topic that lends itself
游戏这是一个适合自己的话题
to a very long discussion and quite a
经过很长时间的讨论，
complicated one but we'll touch on the
复杂的一个，但我们将涉及
main points and position it to the
要点并定位到
landscape of topics we're discussing and
我们正在讨论的主题以及
so the strategy the striking point are
所以策略的重点是
repeated games as we know a repeated
我们知道重复的游戏
game is simply a game in normal form for
游戏只是一种普通形式的游戏
example that will repeat over and over
这个例子会一遍又一遍地重复
again for example we play prisoner's
再例如，我们扮演囚犯
dilemma once twice three times maybe
两次困境两次，也许
finite time maybe an infinite number of
有限的时间也许是无限的
time then we accumulate all the rewards
时间，然后我们积累所有的奖励
all the time to sum over all rewards
一直在总结所有奖励
stochastic gamely is a generalization of
随机博弈是对
it where we play games repeatedly but
它是我们反复玩游戏的地方，但是
not necessarily the same game so we play
不一定是同一游戏，所以我们玩
a game depending on how we played that
取决于我们如何玩的游戏
game let's say prisoner's dilemma we
游戏让我们说囚徒的困境
each got some payoff but depending on
每个人都有一些回报，但取决于
how we play the game we also probable
我们如何玩游戏，我们也可能
probabilistically transition to some
概率性地过渡到一些
other game play that in turn and the
依次进行的其他游戏和
process continues a graphical way to
过程继续以图形方式
look at it is here if if this here is a
看这是这里，如果这是一个
repeated game where you play the same
重复游戏，您玩同样的游戏
game over and over again here you play
在这里玩一遍又一遍的游戏
the game and then if you happen to play
游戏，然后如果您碰巧玩
this your transition to this game if you
这是您向该游戏的过渡，如果您
happen to just play this you maybe
碰巧只是玩这个，你也许
transition to the same game if you play
如果您玩的话，过渡到同一个游戏
this you change your transition here if
如果你改变这里的过渡
you play this maybe you'll play this
你玩这个也许你会玩这个
game again and so on from each game you
再玩一次，依此类推
transition probabilistically to toe it
概率过渡到脚趾
to other games this is a stochastic game
对其他游戏来说这是一个随机的游戏
formally speaking it's it's the
正式来说是
following tuple it's a lot of notation
以下元组有很多符号
but the concept is exactly so we have is
但是这个概念正是我们所拥有的
a finite set of states Q we have a set
有限的一组状态Q我们有一组
of players we have a set of actions
我们有一系列行动
where
哪里
actions are available to two specific
有两个特定的操作可用
players of a sub I is the action
子我是玩家的动作
available player I and then we have two
可用的球员我，然后我们有两个
two functions we have the transition
我们有两个功能过渡
probability function so depending on the
概率函数，因此取决于
state were in and on the actions we took
陈述我们采取的行动
we move to each of any of the other
我们移到其他任何一个
states or the very same state with a
状态或与一个状态完全相同的状态
certain probability as governed by this
受此约束的特定概率
probability distribution and and
概率分布和
similarly a reward is the reward
同样，奖励就是奖励
function which tells us if in a certain
告诉我们如果
State a certain action profile was taken
说明采取了某种行动
by the agents then this is a reward to
由代理商，那么这是对
to that particular agent to eat each of
给那个特工吃
the agents so our sub I is a reward to
代理商，所以我们的子我是对
two agent I that's the formal definition
我是正式的两个代理人
notice that it's sort of assumes
请注意，这是一种假设
implicitly that you have the same action
暗含你有相同的动作
spaces here but you could define it
这里有空格，但您可以定义它
otherwise it simply would involve more
否则，它将涉及更多
notations or nothing inherently
表示法或本来就不存在
important about the action spaces being
关于动作空间很重要
the same in the different games within
在不同的游戏中相同
this stochastic game so just a few final
这个随机的游戏，所以最后几场
comments on it first of all as we as we
首先像我们一样评论它
saw this obviously general generalizes
看到这显然可以概括
the notion of a repeated game but it
重复游戏的概念，但它
also generalizes the notion of an MDP or
也概括了MDP或
a Markov decision process if a if a
马尔可夫决策过程，如果
sarcastic game if a repeated game is a
如果重复的游戏是一个讽刺游戏
stochastic game with only one game a
一个只有一个游戏的随机游戏
Markov decision process on MVP is a game
MVP的马尔可夫决策过程是一个游戏
with only one player and so you have
只有一个玩家，所以你有
States there where the agents take agent
代理商所在的国家
takes an action receives a remediate
采取行动得到补救
reward and probably move to some other
奖励并可能转移到其他人
state and the only difference is that he
状态，唯一的区别是他
is the only actor in the setting I
是背景中我唯一的演员
mentioned this because well empty peas
提到这个是因为豌豆很好
have been studied
已经研究过
naturally in a variety of disciplines
自然地在各种学科中
from optimization to computer science to
从优化到计算机科学，再到
pure math and beyond but also these two
纯粹的数学，以及超越这两个
perspectives of generalization repeated
泛化观点重复
games and of MVPs give you a sense for
游戏和MVP可以带给您
the theory and investigations into
理论与研究
stochastic games so from repeated games
重复游戏中的随机游戏
we inherit the definitions of different
我们继承了不同的定义
ways of the aggregating rewards over
汇总奖励的方式
time you can have limited average
有限的平均时间
rewards future discounted rewards
奖励未来的折扣奖励
whereas from the literature on
而根据文献
optimization and on MVPs we get notions
优化，在MVP上我们有了概念
such as stationarity and Markovian
例如平稳性和马尔可夫式
strategies these have to do with we also
这些与我们有关的策略
have notions of reach ability about the
有关于
structure of the underlying transition
基本过渡的结构
probability and so again these are
概率，这些又是
issues that are involved that we won't
我们不会涉及的问题
get to into more in this lecture but at
在本讲座中深入了解，但在
least we flagged their existence
至少我们标记了它们的存在